most common errors you're going to get
with go dependencies on private modules
and this video is going to relate to a
lot of different things all at the same
time but it's for people who want to
build go projects that have dependencies
on private modules I made another video
where I go through the five different
ways to get around this this one is
going to have more Hands-On it's going
to be more this is exactly what the
error looks like and this is how you fix
the error and we're also going to talk
about some an option number six uh which
you may not have thought of called go
vendoring uh to get around this problem
particularly in the case where your
entire Enterprise is effectively full of
private repost now because you are on go
Enterprise Cloud which has turned every
one of your otherwise public Enterprise
server repos into private inner Source
repos under a specific organization
which go hates go absolutely hates
private things it wasn't Deni it wasn't
set up to do it everything that's ever
been done to have to deal with private
modules has always been tacked on uh and
sometimes in a kind of not so clear way
so we're going to go through all those
errors right now the first err is this
so let me let me summarize really quick
we have we have a couple of accounts
here we have the GH Test 2 account which
is um this is the you know it's just an
account on GitHub where we're creating a
an application that we want to use our
package so we're going to go use this we
we want to use this private package
which has print hello world in it and
this is um by the way these um these t-o
windows are uh the equivalent to
separate accounts as if I was log into
separate machines you can see the
machine the account here and and you can
see they're all the same container but
it's effectively different accounts so
pretend like these are different users
all right
um and the all of these users are under
the same organization the organization
is um uh GH test org 2 so so these these
um repos I'm sorry these users these
these GitHub accounts have access read
access to each other and that's covered
in a separate video but they're all
under the same organization so so to be
very precise rwx Rob GH test2 account
has ownership and and read write access
to go command with priv de only nobody
else in the organization can see that
however its dependency is and this is
why we're doing the video it has a
dependency on a repo that was that
started out owned by somebody else and
got moved into the organization as if
simula simulating a migration such as
under Enterprise cloud in source
it has been this private go package was
migrated into here and we're going to
now look at that so here it is um the
first thing you'll notice is when we did
the migration actually I forgot to
change the module path line it is very
important that you understand if you are
migrating to a different GitHub location
your go code will have to be touched it
will have to be changed you'll have to
change the module line as you can see
here and you'll have have to upgrade the
patch level of the version through
tagging so you know you can look at the
tag whoops uh there it is version 002
there's a little Pearl errow there
because of the container so um so anyway
that that that is that's what's up and
we uh so so again the the the library
that we now have a dependency on uh that
contains the code we want to run in this
private repo is now owned by
this organization and the GH test one
user is has because it's you know test
one user is also the owner of the
organization in this case so the RBX Rob
GH test org 2 is the organizational path
name for the package but you can see
that this is under the GH test one
account it's as if this account user uh
is just working on this and maintaining
this so so anybody with right access in
the
organization uh I have GH Rob uh I have
Rob test one test two and test three all
of these people have different
membership on the different things as
you can see um this this person has
ownership has admin on everything
because they're the owner of the
organization um we have DH Test 2 which
has a bunch of private repos and you can
see they have read on everything Only By
Design um uh for the record this used to
have admin access on private go package
because it was transferred to the
organization by the this this um this GH
Test 2 account originally and I had to
take away uh the readon access to that
repo um this is probably the content for
another video but whatever so RBX Rob
test 3 uh we can see here what access
they have same as the other one they
have no no access to anything so so this
is a simulated
organization um with you know simulated
access to the organization as you would
set up in a GitHub Enterprise Cloud
environment um and you can see that each
of those accounts has you know one of
three levels uh of access to be granted
to each repo by default by the way any
new uh member of the organization has
readon access I don't know if your
organization has set up to do that same
thing I don't even know if my
organization is set up to do that same
default but that is the default on
GitHub um so what does this have to go
to do with go now right so so we now
have this
library that has been tagged um viic uh
I forget what my tag command is
actually uh latest and exit no let's see
test tag F push
no uh viic latest I don't remember how
to there it is get
tag get tag I guess that just gets okay
so so those are the tags on here um and
we had to do that when we were doing the
migration so this what I'm trying to say
here is that this this this private go
package is private but it is now ready
to be used the problem is that it's
private it's private and so I'm going to
show you now the errors that you're
going to get that are very very cryptic
when you're first just coming to go here
like what the heck is this error about
and you just want to use the thing right
so the first thing you might do is you
write your little program you put your
little import here um and then you you
know you go to build it and you forget
that you need to do a goed it's very
common and you see this error it's like
nope you need to get this module you got
to add it I'm like okay I'm going to do
that so you come over here and you do
your go getet you cut and paste this and
you're going to do your goget and you're
going to get this eror what the heck is
this error okay so this this error says
basically I have no way to even check on
the repo this is go trying to use git to
get the information by default for this
module the module dependency the private
go package module and it can't do it
because it assumes https authentication
by default now there's two ways to get
around this problem the first way you're
going to read about a lot and that's
using a personal access token which is
an https thing uh there's there's
another way is some people will say is
the official way and that is to use a
netrc file uh which go will observe
above beyond anything else before it
even gets to get right if there's an NRC
file who use the htps credentials in the
NRC file for a specific domain and it
will go get those things you can look at
those two ways uh the most common
workaround for this however is and and
this is kind of intuitive is to get um
go to use SSH for GitHub because GitHub
you know most of the time all of you
know most of us are using still using
SSH keys for that because we don't want
it to deal with refreshing a a pat every
180 days or whatever um even though we
might be using the get up command line
tool which of course requires a personal
access token that is a deep deep Rabbit
Hole we're not going to go down now what
we want to do is get this to use SSH
instead of HTTP so the command for that
and you can actually type this in but
I'm going to show you the command I
actually cuted up here um um someplace
there we go this command is is a good
one to memorize because you can put it
in your cicd if you want to put this in
your cicd actions you can put it as a
run line in your get up actions um and
it this will actually tell uh this will
tell get itself to use SSH instead of
https by the way do not forget this
trailing slash I must the last 40
minutes on that so by doing that you can
add that in there if you want to you can
just go in and add it instead you can go
in here and add it right here and add
those lines uh just like anything else
okay as soon as you have that now go is
is going to use git and when it tries to
use Git it will know to try to use SSH
instead of
https so this is go attempting to use
git and then git seeing its
configuration saying hey for good
hub.com domain if you're getting an
https try SSH instead so that's how
that's what's going on behind the scenes
and so then we do our Gog get and we get
another erir and you're like you're like
pulling the remaining hair you have out
what the hell is this about this is
because you're get um your go is trying
to do its regular very secure check of
the check sum to make sure that your
package you're trying to get is the
actual package and so there is a cash
out there that it protects you and by
the way this is a good thing this is a
good thing you should be happier getting
this thereor this means that you're
protected this means that go is trying
to make sure that you're actually
downloading the thing that hasn't been
tampered with unlike npm did some years
ago which allowed the biggest internet
worm and history so you know you want to
be happy that this exists but right now
it's an
because it's like um you know we are not
it's trying it's doing some really
stupid stuff it's like why what terminal
what it's trying to prompt you different
things this is really just because it's
trying to authenticate against the proxy
server the check some Check Pro and
there's a lot of ways to get around this
but the most standard way to get around
this is to set go private uh and go
private uses a glob so you can say for
github.com in this case we're going to
be very precise going to say I don't
want this thing to um be you know I only
want this one to be if you if you just
put this part without the other part it
will do it for the entire thing that
means it will never check check sums at
all there's another there are two more
uh environment variables there's go
there's go uh there's go no sum and go I
think no proxy and you might want to
read about those search about those
doesn't understand them uh they allow
different granularity in in how you do
this but for our cases right now we just
want to add this and definitely you
might want to add this to your um this I
mean either you're adding it to your
cicd and you're setting that environment
variable or you're adding it to if
you're just doing an you know an
interactive user you probably want to
put that in your um in your own
configuration file you know your bash RC
somehow um but by exporting that now
when we to do that same command now
we're going to get through and you can
see that it went ahead and it added it
it added version 0.0.2 instead of that
big long 0.0.0 no you know without a tag
by the way please tag your please please
please tag your go packages I do I have
to say this I guess I do people so many
people don't on major projects they're
untagged uh they have dependencies on
them and the whole I made a whole you
ranty video about people who not using
some particularly for go and please go
check that out so you want that right
even if it's that
level okay so now what can I do can I do
my build go build this is the success
the moment of success I could go build I
could go install and I can do go command
blah blah blah right uh and I mean you
guys know this right I could do actually
let's do this let's do go uh go build
um uh Dash show hello I think that'll
work right Dello yay hello world and
that that works right but but here's the
problem what happens when you want to
put all that into cicd of some
kind right how are you going to do that
that gets very very messy and all I'm
going to say is go watch the video about
the five different ways to build an
cicd um and it talks about this this
pretend idea of having multiple users
right we on the command line we just
added go priv but how on Earth would you
authenticate as you know this particular
User it's a tough question and there's a
45 minute video about it but there's
also a much better answer and it
involves something called go vendoring
which should probably have its own video
but I'm going to show it to you anyway
right here
um
uh every Super why would you complain in
the middle of my video about using
Linux just to troll me I guess um not
yet we're doing a video here and and
then we'll be done in a second okay so
so let's do this all right we've got
hello here but so let's let's consider a
couple cases once again what happens
when that that person there's a there's
many reasons you know what I'm going to
do a separate video about go vendoring
I'm going to do a separate video about
go vendoring go watch that other video
you ready go watch the video about go
vendoring because it might help you get
past the problem this video has been
about how to get past those major errors
and do your builds and we'll end the
video there and I'll make another video
about vendoring and I'll do it right
away